之前在那些即将死去的人身上......
Previously on
Those About To Die...
图密善的那个人是谁？
Who was that man with Domitian?
- 他的名字叫特纳克斯。- 我需要更多地了解他。
- His name is Tenax.
- I need to know more about him.
那些股份被你丈夫偷走了。
Those shares were
stolen by your husband.
奉提图斯皇帝之命，
By order of Emperor Titus,
允许在马克西姆斯竞技场运行
permission to run
in Circus Maximus
特此退出黄金派系。
is hereby withdrawn
from the Gold Faction.
你能赤手空拳杀死什么？
What could you kill
with your bare hands?
抑制！
Restrain!
我会好好展示他的死。
I'll make a good
show of his death.
我要从你那里拿走一切。
I'm gonna take
everything from you.
乌尔苏斯？
Ursus?
你留下来烧死的那个男孩。
The boy you left to burn.
乌尔苏斯，乌尔苏斯。
Ursus, Ursus.
你做了什么？
What have you done?
你们这些小混蛋！
You little fuckers!
请！加油！帮助！
Please! Come on! Help!
今天不要这样做！
Don't do this today!
乌尔苏斯。
Ursus.
乌尔苏斯！
Ursus!
我会敞开心扉。
I'll open up.
我们需要更多的石板。
We need more slates.
还有另一位店员处理挥杆赌注。
And another clerk to
handle the swing bets.
- 你听到了吗？-是的。
- Did you hear me?
- Yes.
这被留在了门口。
This was left at the door.
读给我听。
Read it to me.
- 这可能是个人的，我...-只。。。
- It might be personal, I...
- Just...
做吧。
Do it.
不要感到羞耻。
Don't be ashamed.
我的人民已经有1000年没有书面语言了。
My people had no written
language for 1,000 years.
- 我们的过去是沉默的。- 我不感到羞耻。
- Our past is silent.
- I'm not ashamed.
只是阅读它。
Just read it.
大声地。
Out loud.
对我来说。
To me.
“您在每个比赛日结束时的所有奖金，
"All of your winnings at
the end of each race day,
放在二楼的角落房间，
put in the corner
room, second floor,
在Cispian Hill的岛内。
in your insula at Cispian Hill.
这是我沉默的代价。
It's the price of my silence."
没有人知道这一点。
No one learns of this.
赌小金马的人。
The one who bet
the little gold horse.
大个子，脸上有烧伤疤痕。
Big, with the burn
scars on his face.
-找到他。- 我们一直在关注......
- Find him.
- We've been keeping our eyes...
我说现在就去找他！看看每一个博彩酒馆，
I said find him, now! Look
in every betting tavern,
每个妓院，每个排水沟，每个粪坑。
every brothel, every
gutter, every shithole.
找到他！
Find him!
你在外面等我。
You wait for me out there.
吃。
Eat.
嘿，你是这批人中最好的。
Hey, you're the
best out of this lot.
我有事要你做。
I've got something
for you to do.
Cispian Hill有一间公寓，二楼，角落房间。
There's an apartment on Cispian
Hill, second floor, corner room.
我知道。
I know it.
去那里。环顾四周。看看你能看到什么，
Go there. Take a look
around. See what you can see,
谁在看。隐身。
who's watching. Be invisible.
嘿，先吃饭。
Hey, eat first.
首先是 Suburra。
The Suburra first.
我有一些想法，他可能藏在哪里。
I've got some ideas
where he might be hiding.
姐姐，这个是我给你拿的。
Sister, I got this for you.
谢谢。
Thank you.
特纳克斯，我找到了他。
Tenax, I found him.
那个伤痕累累的大个子。这边。
The big, scarred man. This way.
拜托，拜托。别杀我。
Please, please. Don't kill me.
别杀我！
Don't kill me!
继续寻找。
Keep looking.
氙！氙！氙！氙！
Xenon! Xenon! Xenon! Xenon!
加油！
Come on!
氙！氙！氙！氙！
Xenon! Xenon! Xenon! Xenon!
不是天蝎座。
Not Scorpus.
加油！
Come on!
去！
Go!
是的。
Yes.
哎呀！
Hyah!
是的！
Yeah!
氙！氙！
Xenon! Xenon!
看来 Xenon 正在赚取他的薪水。
It seems Xenon is
earning his salary.
他肯定是。
He most certainly is.
谢谢。谢谢大家。
Thank you. Thank you, all.
这是一场既崇高又当之无愧的胜利。
A victory both
noble and deserved.
谢谢。
Thank you.
祝贺。
Congratulations.
闭上你的嘴。
Shut your mouth.
哦，来吧，第三名。
Oh, come on, third place.
这比人们对那些老唠叨的期望要好得多。
That's much better than one
would expect with those old nags.
我真的不能说我想念他们。
I can't really say I miss them.
今天对你来说不太顺利。
Didn't go so well for you today.
滚开。
Piss off.
你为什么生我的气？
Why are you angry with me?
我不生气你签了白衣军团。
I'm not angry that you
signed for the White.
我受伤了。伤害你不信任我。
I'm hurt. Hurt you
didn't trust me.
发生了一些事情。你需要来。
Something has happened.
You need to come.
尼卡。
Nica.
来吧，来吧。
Come, come.
尼卡。
Nica.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
天蝎座排在第三位。
Scorpus comes in third.
天蝎座他妈的第三！
Scorpus fucking third!
他妈的第三。
Fucking third.
他妈的。
Fuck.
安全睡眠。
Sleep safe.
睁一只眼。
One eye open.
我从来不认识我的母亲。
I never knew my mother.
费利克斯
Felix,
在她生病之前，他记得她。
he remembered her
before she got sick.
他说她真的很漂亮。
He said she was really pretty.
像你一样。
Like you.
令堂。。。
Your mother...
她在云端，
she's up there in the clouds,
看着你。
watching you.
我把他送到了那里。
I sent him there.
我早该知道的。
I should have known.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about this?
他杀了一个孩子。
He killed a child.
快点。
Hurry up.
哦。嘿。
Oh. Hey.
仅此而已。
That's all of it.
听我说。
Listen to me.
你们俩一直注视着这个地方。
The two of you watch
this place at all times.
比菲利克斯躲得更好。
Hide better than Felix did.
你看到了发生在他身上的事情。
You saw what happened to him.
如果那个伤痕累累的大个子来了，你们中的一个人跟着他
If the big scarred man
comes, one of you follows him
另一个来找我。
and the other one
comes to find me.
要非常小心。
Be very careful.
一个祈祷的Tenax。
A praying Tenax.
我是一个赌徒。
I'm a gambling man.
我会尝试一次。
I'll try anything once.
你为什么起床？
Why are you up?
我睡不着。
I couldn't sleep.
菲利克斯是20年前的我。
Felix was me 20 years ago.
我住在马厩附近的腹地。
I lived in the underbelly,
near the stables.
流浪狗？
A stray?
我一直很喜欢马。所以当我到达罗马时，
I always liked horses.
So when I got to Rome,
感觉像是要去的地方。
it felt like the place to go.
靠近马厩。
Near the stables.
我们睡在一大堆里，我们30或40个人
We slept in a big
pile, 30 or 40 of us
为了温暖和安全。
for warmth and for safety.
好像有这样的事情。
As if there was such a thing.
但你爬了出来。
But you crawled
your way out of it.
我拾荒了
I scavenged
一次吃一点食物。
one bit of food at a time.
一个丑陋的差事，
One ugly errand,
挨了一打，挨了一打，
one beating taken,
one beating given,
一把刀到肋骨，一个固定的比赛，
one knife to the
ribs, one fixed race,
买了一套公寓，一步一个脚印。
one apartment bought,
one step at a time.
要么崛起，要么死亡，
Rise or die,
罗马方式。
the Roman way.
在罗马之前，
And before Rome,
他知道什么？
what does he know?
这个要钱的人。
This one who demands the money.
我敢打赌，要解决这个问题。
Something to deal
with this, I wager.
嗯，痊愈了。
Hmm, healed well.
如果有这样的事情。
If there is such a thing.
睡。
Sleep.
- 我们在赛车吗，氙气？- 今天没有比赛。
- Are we racing, Xenon?
- There is no race today.
你从来没有玩得开心过？
You never have any fun?
最后像你一样？
And end up like you?
这对我来说似乎并不好玩。
It doesn't seem like fun to me.
嗯，是的。
Well, it is.
对于一个小男孩来说，这是一个大行李箱。
That's a big trunk
for a small boy.
我们跑去加入军团，是吗？
Running off to join
the legions, are we?
妈妈说我们要搬进大房子。
Mother says we're
moving into a big house.
我要有自己的房间。
I'm going to have my own room.
那么请允许我帮助你，阁下。
Then allow me to help you
with that, Your Eminence.
骑上马鞍。
Saddle up.
丰索亚，我看到我儿子让你去工作了。
Fonsoa, I see my son
has put you to work.
大个子，我需要你的帮助。
Big man, I need your help.
哦，是的。
Oh, yes.
那么，去哪里呢？
So, where to?
埃斯奎林。
The Esquiline.
这是一栋带蓄水池和花园的大房子。
It's a big house with a
cistern and a garden.
这只是我母亲的一个朋友的家。
It's just the home of
a friend of my mother.
只要知道你是你所属的地方。
Just knowing that you
are where you belong.
你找到你的归属了吗？
And have you found
where you belong?
你美丽的贝蒂卡不是在呼唤你吗？
Isn't your beautiful
Baetica calling to you?
确实如此。
It was.
好吧，我感谢你让这个地方对他来说是可以忍受的。
Well, I thank you for making
this place bearable for him.
我和我的弟弟一起练习。
I had practice with
my little brother.
我的母亲死于分娩，
My mother died giving birth,
我们的哥哥总是和马一起离开。
and our older brother was
always off with the horses.
所以它落在我身上。
So it fell to me.
即使在天堂里，也有艰难的时期。
There were tough
times, even in paradise.
方索阿，
Fonsoa,
你忘了我吗？
did you forget about me?
我们现在应该走了。
We should be going now.
- 让我来帮忙。- 不，拜托。
- Let me help.
- No, please.
你已经做得够多了。
You've done enough already.
请。
Please.
- 跳上去。-哦。
- Jump on.
- Oh.
-准备？-是的。
- Ready?
- Yes.
你要告诉我你在想什么吗？
Are you going to tell
me what's on your mind?
你告诉所有人，我会回家的。
You are telling everybody
that I will be returning home.
是的。
Yes.
一旦我们赚到了足够的钱，你就要去Leptis Magna了。
Once we've earned enough for
your passage to Leptis Magna.
如果我等一下不是更好吗？
Wouldn't it be
better if I waited?
我们可以作为一个家庭回来。
We could return as a family.
不，只有上帝才能说
No, only the God can say
需要多长时间才能解救你的兄弟姐妹。
how long it will take to
free your brother and sister.
我需要你在我不在的时候管理交易站。
And I need you to run the
trading post in my absence.
Seeno可以做到这一点。
Seeno can do that.
哦，你宁愿留在这里，
Oh, you'd rather stay here,
在这个蛇窝里。
in this den of serpents.
罗马是一个太危险的地方。
Rome is far too
dangerous a place.
嗯嗯。
Mm-mm.
我很惊讶我什至不得不告诉你这个，
I'm surprised I even
have to tell you this,
鉴于我们的经验。
given our experience.
我在这件事上没有发言权吗？
Do I have no say in this matter?
母亲，我们一路走来
Mother, we have
come all this way
到世界的中心。
to the center of the world.
我只是想亲眼看看其中的一些。
I just wish to see
some of it for myself.
你的兄弟姐妹正在为他们的生命而战，
Your brother and sister
are fighting for their lives,
你说得好像这是一次伟大的冒险。
and you talk as if this
is some great adventure.
我必须来这里救你
I had to come here
to save you from
最后在摊位上成为一个妓女。
ending up a whore in a stall.
夸梅很可能会死在竞技场上
Kwame may very
well die in the arena
因为你的愚蠢。
because of your foolishness.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
我无意残忍。
It is not my
intention to be cruel.
我的大女儿对这个家庭负有责任。
My oldest daughter has a
responsibility to this family.
我不会自私。
I won't suffer selfishness.
母亲，你不是唯一一个受苦的人。
You are not the only one
who is suffering, Mother.
光环。
Aura.
我本可以派奴隶来换取你的财物。
I could have sent slaves
for your belongings.
这没什么大不了的。
It was no trouble.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我的人民将从这里拿走它。
My people will
take it from here.
祝你好运。给你们俩。
Good luck to you. To you both.
谢谢。也给你。
Thank you. To you as well.
你迟到了。
You're late.
听着，一个新郎，瘦小的那个，
Listen, one of the
grooms, the skinny one,
说红色派系正在寻求雇用一名后备司机。
said the Red Faction is
looking to hire a reserve driver.
我们为黄金派系工作，兄弟。
We work for the
Gold Faction, brother.
- 什么黄金派系？- Tenax 说他会修复它。
- What Gold Faction?
- Tenax said he'll fix it.
如果他不这样做呢？
And what if he doesn't?
好的，我们会按照你的计划去做。
All right, we'll you
go with your plan.
我们被红色派系雇用，
We get hired by the Red Faction,
让特纳克斯保留我们的马匹，并因侮辱而杀了我们。
have Tenax keep our
horses and kill us for the insult.
好主意。
Great idea.
Xenon 在这方面很擅长。
Xenon is great at this.
是的，他是。
Yeah, he is.
奇怪的是，人群没有要求拿到木剑。
It's strange that the crowd has not
demanded to get the wooden sword.
他们做到了，三次。
They did, three times.
每当他们给予他自由时，
Each time they
granted him his freedom,
他告诉他们把它推到他们的屁股上。
he told them to
shove it up their arses.
什么样的男人会选择留在赛场上？
What type of man chooses
to stay in the arena?
一个不担心失败的人。
One who's not
worried about losing.
角斗士
Gladiators,
走近一点。
come closer.
为了庆祝我们的皇帝提图斯的婚礼，
To celebrate the wedding
of our emperor, Titus,
已经召集了特殊的游戏。
special games have been called.
婚礼什么时候举行？
When is the wedding?
我要参加吗？
Am I to attend?
他们说，这已经发生在夜深人静的时候。
It happened already in
the dead of night, they say.
尽管如此，它还是需要庆祝的游戏。
Nonetheless, it calls
for games of celebration.
Flamma 将引领这场奇观。
Flamma will lead the spectacle.
他的对手，亲自选择
His opponent, chosen personally
作者：Aedile Ludi， Flavius Domitianus
by the Aedile Ludi,
Flavius Domitianus
不是别人，正是我们的小狮子杀手，
is no other than
our little Lion Killer,
夸。
Kwame.
当然，他需要一些帮助
He will, of course,
need some help
使它持续足够长的时间，可以称为娱乐。
to make it last long enough
to be called entertainment.
奥齐，普里齐，
Ozzi, Prizzi,
你将有幸与夸梅一起死在弗拉玛的手中。
you will have the honor of dying
with Kwame at Flamma's hands.
对不起，兄弟。
I am sorry, brother.
来
Come,
回到训练。
back to training.
我恨不得我的死让新皇后失望。
I would hate for my death to
disappoint the new empress.
你怎么能抛弃白人？
How could you desert the Whites?
Xenon 现在为蓝军开车。
Xenon drives for the Blues now.
你对我们派系的忠诚在哪里？
And where's your
loyalty to our faction?
我的忠诚与我的男人氙气在一起。
My loyalty is with my man Xenon.
他去哪里，我就去哪里。
Where he goes, I go.
好吧，你们俩将成为一对可爱的情侣。
Well, you two are going
to make a lovely couple.
但这场比赛是肯定的。
But this race is a sure thing.
绿党只经营马雷马诺母马，
The Greens run only
Maremano mares,
雨后无与伦比。
unbeatable after rainfall.
如果木星今晚打开天空，
If Jupiter opens
the skies tonight,
他会的，你会把你的钱增加三倍。
which he will, you'll
triple your money.
那为什么要告诉我这一切呢？
So why tell me all this?
好吧，酒馆里没有人会相信我的功劳。
Well, nobody in the
tavern will take my credit.
- 但是如果你在我面前 20 塞斯特斯...... - 对，对。
- But if you front me 20 sesterces...
- Right, right.
我正在努力帮助你。
I'm trying to help you.
就像你通过赌走她的财产来帮助你的妻子一样。
Like you helped your wife
by gambling away her fortune.
任何有眼睛的人都知道，种族是一个解决方案。
Anybody with eyes
knows that race was a fix.
Tenax 操了我以获得这些股份。
Tenax fucked me
to get those shares.
我警告过你这种谈话。
I warned you about
that sort of talk.
他是怎么让斯科普斯忍住的，嗯？
How did he get Scorpus
to hold back, huh?
我永远不会知道。
I'll never know.
Tenax 操了我以获得这些股份。
Tenax fucked me
to get those shares.
弄脏别人的地板
Stain someone else's floor
用你的血。
with your blood.
所以我听说你把你的派系股份输给了Tenax。
So I hear you lost your
faction shares to Tenax.
有人想和你说话。
Someone wants to speak to you.
来。
Come.
欢迎。
Welcome.
是鲁弗斯，是吗？
It's Rufus, yes?
我听说你和Tenax打过交道，
I'm told you've had
dealings with Tenax,
他们称之为苏布拉之王的那个。
the one they call the
King of the Suburra.
请坐。
Please, sit.
原谅我的外表。
Forgive my appearance.
我没想到会见到犹太人的女王。
I wasn't expecting an audience
with the Queen of the Jews.
我听说他操纵了比赛，偷走了你在蓝色派系的股份。
I'm told he rigged the race and
stole your shares of the Blue Faction.
当萨琳娜看到我的所作所为时，她眼中的羞愧。
The shame in Salena's eyes
when she saw what I'd done.
我美丽的儿子。
My beautiful son.
我突然想到，我们也许可以互相帮助。
It occurs to me that we may
be able to help one another.
一个问题。
A question.
你有没有在皇帝的兄弟的陪伴下见过这个Tenax？
Have you ever seen this Tenax in
the company of the Emperor's brother?
不是用我自己的眼睛。
Not with my own eyes.
但我被告知，Tenax是图密善的客户。
But I'm told that Tenax
is Domitian's client.
有传言说是图密善
Rumor has it that
it was Domitian
谁批准了特纳克斯的黄金派系。
who approved
Tenax's Gold Faction.
这就是你给我一把匕首的地方
This is where you
give me a dagger
让我割开特纳克斯的喉咙？
and ask me to
slit Tenax's throat?
我向你保证，有更有能力的人来完成这项任务。
I assure you there are more
competent man for that task.
我不希望你杀了Tenax。
I don't want you to kill Tenax.
我要你向他求工作。
I want you to ask him for work.
没关系。
It is all right.
告诉我你的名字。
Tell me your name.
阿伦，你去哪儿了？
Ahren, where have you been?
哦，你变大了。
Oh, you're getting big.
夸
Kwame,
有睡眠吗？
any sleep?
为什么要把最后的时光浪费在睡眠上？
Why waste my last
moments on sleep?
我的妻子林扎和我的儿子阿伦。
My wife, Linza,
and my son Ahren.
你会尊重我们的。
You would honor us.
请，请过来，坐。
Please, please come, sit.
我有两个姐妹也在罗马。
I have two sisters also in Rome.
我不会再见到他们了。
I won't see them again.
你丈夫打得很好。
Your husband fights well.
他会赢得木剑。
He will win the wooden sword.
所以我祈祷。
So I pray.
当我这样做时，
And when I do,
我们三个人将返回武里。
the three of us
will return to Buri.
我父亲在那里给我留下了一个农场。
My father left me a farm there.
鹅，几只山羊。
Geese, a couple of goats.
我和琳扎会同时繁殖，
Me and Linza will breed both,
还有我们自己，生了更多的孩子，很多。
and ourselves as well, making
more babies, lots of them.
你想成为大哥吗？
Would you like to
be a big brother?
是的，你会是一个好大哥。
Yes, you'd be a
good big brother.
向众神祈求的一件好事。
A good thing to
ask the Gods for.
婴儿、鹅和山羊。
Babies, geese and goats.
不，我......
No, I...
我请求众神保护你，我的兄弟。
I ask the Gods to
protect you, my brother.
你浪费了对众神的恳求
You waste an
entreaty to the Gods
给我的？
for me?
不浪费。
Not wasted.
也许有一天我会参观你的农场
Perhaps one day
I will visit your farm
并认识你的孩子。
and meet your children.
别忘了山羊。
And don't forget the goats.
它的疯狂。
The madness of it.
提多娶了他的表妹。
Titus married his cousin.
省级什么都没有。
Provincial nothing.
要是我认识一个人就好了，
If only I knew a man,
未稀释的贵族血统，
undiluted Patrician blood,
谁可能会登上铜椅。
who might ascend
the curule chair.
一个有着辉煌军事记录的人，
Someone with a
brilliant military record,
对命令感到满意。
comfortable with command.
我们以前跳过这个舞，安东尼娅。
We've done this
dance before, Antonia.
从这里到亚历山大港的每一位贵族
Every Patrician from
here to Alexandria
已经跳了这支舞，现在正在做。
has done this dance
and is doing it now.
参议院在危机时刻向你求助。
The Senate turns to
you in moments of crisis.
他们中的许多人会为了看到你在铜椅上而杀人。
Many of them will kill to
see you on the curule chair.
小心。我们在自己家里说的话是一回事，
Careful. What we say inside
our own home is one thing,
但这样的对话在这些墙外
but such a conversation
outside these walls
是无法解铸的骰子。
is a die that cannot be uncast.
你不确定我是否能成为一个好皇后吗？
Are you unsure if I were
to make a good empress?
亲爱的，这是我确信的一件事。
That, my dear, is the one
thing of which I am sure.
皇后。多么可爱的词。
Empress. What a lovely word.
但不如皇帝可爱。
But not as lovely as Emperor.
嘘！
Shh!
内战是有代价的。
The Civil War comes at a cost.
参议员们，甚至是我阵营的参议员们，都记得这一点。
Senators, even those in
my camp, remember that.
火灾发生后，元老院和暴徒都反对尼禄。
The Senate and the mob both
turned against Nero after the fires.
火灾？
Fires?
你会把火炬点燃罗马，以满足我们的野心。
You'd put a torch to Rome
to satisfy our ambition.
为了你，为了我们的儿子
For you and for our son
为了我们的家庭，
and for our family,
我会烧毁整个该死的帝国。
I'd burn down the
entire fucking empire.
如果我牺牲了这座城市，我会成为什么样的皇帝
What kind of emperor would
I be if I sacrificed the city
获得对它的统治权？
to obtain dominion over it?
我们不需要火。
We don't need a fire.
我们只需要一个火花。
We just need a spark.
谢谢你，亲爱的。
Thank you, my dear.
出去。
Get out.
- 我们可以谈谈吗？- 我说出去。
- May we speak?
- I said get out.
- 拜托，我...- 如果这是关于股份的
- Please, I...
- If this is about the shares
不管你认为我做了什么来得到他们，
and whatever you
think I did to get them,
不要浪费你的呼吸。
don't waste your breath.
我是来找你的工作的。
I'm here to ask you for work.
- 做什么？- 您需要的任何东西。
- Doing what?
- Anything you need.
没有人会雇用我。
Nobody else will hire me.
这是有充分理由的。
For a good reason.
我少喝酒，从不偷东西。
I drink less and never steal.
至少从你那里。
At least from you.
我从比你强壮得多的人那里听说过。
I've heard that from much
stronger men than you.
我向我的儿子发誓。
I swear it on my son.
一个好的誓言，
A good oath,
但不是来自傻瓜。
but not from a fool.
Tenax，拜托了。
Tenax, please.
我求求你了，拜托了。
I beg you, please.
每天三杯
Three sesterces a day
她说什么你就做什么。
and you do whatever she says.
谢谢你，Tenax...
Thank you, Tenax...
如果你从我这里偷东西，
If you steal from me,
我会砍掉你的手，把它们卖给卡波。
I will cut off your hands
and sell them to Carpo.
谢谢。
Thank you.
妈妈！
Mother!
这是什么？这是什么？
What is it? What is it?
妈妈，夸梅。
Mama, Kwame.
夸。
Kwame.
你知道吗？
Did you know about this?
不。
No.
我能做些什么？
What can I do?
没有办法阻止它。
There's no stopping it.
不是现在。
Not now.
它已经发布，他们已经在集结区了。
It has been posted, they'll
already be at the staging area.
一切都是有代价的。
Everything has a price.
不是这个。不是现在。
Not this. Not now.
但你认识人。
But you know people.
你有影响力，你可以做到。
You have influence
and you can do it.
如果我是皇帝本人，我现在无法阻止这一切。
Were I the Emperor himself,
I couldn't stop this now.
暴徒闻到了血腥味。
The mob smells blood.
我能见到他吗？
Can I see him?
我们向提图斯皇帝致敬
We hail the Emperor Titus
和他的新婚妻子玛西娅皇后。
and his new wife,
the Empress Marcia.
皇帝很高兴地宣布
The Emperor is
pleased to announce
经过数周的饥荒，
that after weeks of famine,
他已经填满了粮仓。
he has filled the granaries.
罗马市民将不再挨饿！
The citizens of Rome
will go hungry no more!
为了纪念他的新婚妻子玛西娅，
And in honor of his
new wife, Marcia,
他提供了一个特别的游戏日！
he offers a special
day of games!
表哥，很高兴再次见到你。
Cousin, good to see you again.
你来得正好，正好赶上看弗拉玛
You arrived just in
time to watch Flamma
为了你的荣誉杀死三个人。
slay three men in your honor.
同样为了纪念你，我暂停了对图密善的监禁。
Also in your honor, I have
suspended Domitian's confinement.
我们可以一起享受光荣的一天。
Together, we can enjoy
a glorious day of games.
谢谢。
My thanks.
我可以把我的两只看门狗留在我身边。
I get to keep my two
watchdogs by my side.
顺便一提
By the way,
那是我妻子的座位。
that's my wife's seat.
让她通过。
Let her through.
儿子。
Son.
妈妈？
Mother?
光环，她是自由的。
Aura, she's free.
- 很快，朱拉也会。-好。
- Soon, Jula will be too.
- Good.
你。。。
You...
你会赢得这场战斗。
You are going to win this fight.
然后我们就可以一起回家了。
Then we can all
go home together.
无论发生什么，我都想把事情做到最好。
Whatever happens, I want
to make the best of things.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
看着我。我。
Look at me. Me.
你出生的那一天，
The day you were born,
你父亲看了你一眼，说：
your father took one
look at you and said,
“狮头神阿佩德马克的灵魂住在我们的儿子身上。”
"The spirit of Apedemak, the
lion-headed god, lives in our son."
他总是比我更迷信。
He was always more
superstitious than me.
老实说，我认为这完全是胡说八道。
Honestly, I thought
that was utter nonsense.
但现在我可以看到它了。
But now I can see it.
我看到了。
I see it.
就像你手中的三叉戟一样清晰。
As clearly as that
trident in your hand.
他们希望你做这是一件可怕的事情，
It is a terrible thing
they expect you to do,
但你必须这样做。
but you must do it.
我知道，母亲。
I know, Mother.
当你到达沙滩时，
When you reach the sand,
不要停下来。
do not stop.
不要放弃，直到他们把你从他身上拉下来。
Do not give up until
they pull you off him.
我不会停下来。
I won't stop.
然后我们会再次见面。
Then we will see
each other again.
说吧，夸梅。
Say it, Kwame.
盖茨。
Gates.
我会再见到你的。
I will see you again.
说啊。
Say it.
我会再见到你的。
I will see you again.
说啊！
Say it!
我会再见到你的。
I will see you again.
我们必须走了。
We must go.
去。
Go.
你是保护我们家庭的狮子。
You are the lion that
protects our family.
弗拉玛！弗拉玛！
Flamma! Flamma!
我们这些即将死去的人，
We who are about to die,
向你致敬。
salute you.
将它们链接起来。
Chain them.
这是怎麽？
What is this?
-移动！-来。来。
- Move!
- Come. Come.
弗拉玛！弗拉玛！
Flamma! Flamma!
留在中间。
Stay in the middle.
对于我们今天的最后一场比赛，
For our final bout today,
伟大的弗拉玛
the great Flamma
将与一支只在神话中为人所知的力量作战。
will do battle with a
force known only in myth.
来自塞壬群岛的邪恶网人。
The wicked net men
from the Siren Islands.
角斗士。。。
Gladiators...
准备！
Ready!
聘！
Engage!
嘿！简单，兄弟！
Hey! Easy, brother!
待在一起。
Stay together.
加油！
Come on!
来，来吧。
Here, come on.
稳住，我亲爱的朋友，稳住。
Steady, my dear friend, steady.
众神表示了他们的恩惠。我就知道。
The Gods show
their favor. I knew it.
不 不。
No, no.
对不起，兄弟。
I'm sorry, brother.
水。
Water.
皇后脸色苍白。
The Empress is
looking rather pale.
也许有人也找到了我哥哥。
Perhaps someone's
found my brother as well.
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
不！
No!
小个子，他表现出极大的勇气
The small one, he
shows great valor
面对一定的失败。
in the face of certain defeat.
看到这样的美德在体育运动中被浪费了，真是可惜。
It's pity to see such
virtue wasted in sport.
看看他的美德如何为他服务
See how his virtue serves him
当弗拉玛用剑刺穿他的心脏时。
when Flamma puts a
sword through his heart.
你是保护我们家庭的狮子。
You are the lion that
protects our family.
加油！
Come on!
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
游戏在你之下，但现在你却在权衡。
The games are so beneath
you, yet now you weigh in.
毅力值得肯定。
Perseverance
deserves recognition.
无论场地多么卑微。
No matter how lowly the venue.
我很好奇。
I'm curious.
砍掉战友的腿属于什么武德？
What martial virtue does cutting
your comrade's leg off fall under?
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
在他的第一场比赛中赢得了暴徒的青睐
Winning the favor of the
mob in his first contest
这可不是一件小事。
is no small feat.
兆头。
Bodes well.
他们能释放他吗？
Might they free him?
不。
No.
他们会想看他一次又一次地战斗。
They'll want to watch
him fight again and again.
如果他幸运的话，他会建立一个追随者，
If he's lucky, he'll
build a following,
更好的对手，更好的赔率。
better opponents, better odds.
也许我匆匆忙忙地和他打赌。
Perhaps I was hasty
to bet against him.
你在我儿子身上有血钱？
You had blood money on my son?
这里是罗马，
This is Rome,
都是血钱。
it's all blood money.
今天比平时更近。
Closer than usual today.
特别是对你来说，不是吗？
Especially for you, no?
我的皇帝，皇后。
My Emperor, Empress.
兄弟，你为什么不给失败者
Brother, why do you
not bestow the loser
带着他的安慰奖？
with his consolation prize?
找掩护。
Take cover.
你向众神祈求火花。
You ask the Gods for a spark.
有你的火花。
There is your spark.